# Mikayla Timm

Website: mtimm100.github.io | Email: mtimm100@gmail.com

## SKILLS

Experienced in researching, developing, and applying machine learning (ML), computer vision, and natural language processing (NLP) techniques for solving problems in research and industry. Proficient with PyTorch, Python, Java, C, UNIX, AWS EC2, and Git. Two computer vision publications and presentations in CVPR workshops and two applied ML publications. Activist for diversity in computing.

## **EXPERIENCE**

**University of Massachusetts Amherst, Amherst, MA** — *Graduate Research Assistant* 

SEPTEMBER 2017 - PRESENT

- Researching computer vision approaches for fine-grained recognition and vision + language.
- Investigating deep learning models for classifying attributes of textures, generating natural language descriptions of texture images, and image retrieval from natural language.
- Collected and refined two novel vision and language datasets using Amazon Mechanical Turk.

**Pinterest, Inc., San Francisco, CA** — Machine Learning Research Intern, Visual Search

MAY 2019 - AUGUST 2019

- Trained and evaluated new and existing vision models for fashion image retrieval through image embeddings conditioned on specific attributes (color, pattern, fabric, gender).
- Implemented and pushed a data pipeline to production for processing and visualizing new data.
- Utilized AWS EC2 P3 instances to train distributed deep models in the cloud on multiple GPUs.

## MIT Lincoln Laboratory, Lexington, MA — *NLP Summer Research Intern*

JUNE 2017 - AUGUST 2017

- Researched NLP techniques for generating word embeddings on inherently multilingual data.
- Designed a pipeline for preprocessing multilingual text corpora, training new embeddings, performing intrinsic evaluations, and visualizing embeddings with dimensionality reduction.

**University of West Florida, Pensacola, FL** — *Undergraduate Research Scholar* 

MAY 2016 - MAY 2017

- Applied ML to classify biometric data obtained from simulated wearable device cyber attacks.
- Implemented supervised learning algorithms to predict outcomes of animals in shelters.

### **University of Massachusetts Amherst, Amherst, MA** — REU Summer Researcher

MAY 2015 - AUGUST 2015

- Developed a system for labeling, training, and classifying animals in camera trap images.
- Automated the **identification** of **individual jaguars** in images using **computer vision**.

## **EDUCATION**

University of Massachusetts Amherst, Amherst, MA - MS in Computer Science

SEPTEMBER 2017 - EXPECTED DECEMBER 2019 | GPA: 3.95

**University of West Florida, Pensacola, FL** - BS in Computer Science, Math minor

AUGUST 2014 - MAY 2017 | GPA: 3.99

#### HONORS AND AWARDS

NSF GRFP Honorable Mention. CVPR Women in Computer Vision Research Travel Grant. CRA-W Grad Cohort Workshop Award. UMass CICS Edward Riseman and Allen Hanson Scholarship. Grace Hopper Celebration of Women in Computing Scholar. UWF Outstanding Undergraduate Student in Comp Sci. UWF Best Student Research Project in Comp Sci. 1st Place in ACM ICPC Southeast Division 2.